Guide to the Libya Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Libya collection
1943-1988
MS 1526
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(2 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the history and current political and economic conditions in Libya.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in this collection is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the history and current political and economic conditions in Libya.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Africa, North -- Periodicals; Libya -- Description and travel; Libya -- Politics and government; Qaddafi, Muammar, 1942-2011
- Inventory, 1977-1988, undated
  - General information pamphlets; brochures, booklets, 1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Green Book: The Solution of the Problem of Democracy 'The Authority of the People' (Part One) and The Solution of the Economic Problem 'Socialism' (Part Two)," by Muammar Quaddafi, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Quaddafi, Muammar: speech at student festival, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Political organizations: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - La Grande Charte Verte des Droits de l'Homme de l'Ère Jamahiriyenne: a charter by Le Congrès Général du Peuple de la Grande Jamahiriya Arabe Libyenne Populaire et Prophète, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Muammar El Gaddafi," by Oriana Fallaci, Entrevista, numero uno, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Ricordo di Tripoli" [picture book], Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, 1943-1944; Accession 1995-M-190
  - Additional printed materials, 1943-1944 (Box 1)